Inventory of the Jan Rowiński collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Posters, circa 1971 (Map case)
  - Learn from Chairman Mao's good student Comrade Liu Yingjun: study Mao Zedong's Ideology, apply Mao Zedong's Ideology, disseminate Mao Zedong's Ideology, defend Mao Zedong's Ideology. Xiang Mao Zhu Xi De Hao Zhan Shi Liu Ying Jun Tong Zhi Xue Xi. Xue Xi Mao Ze Dong Si Xiang, Guan Che Mao Ze Dong Si Xiang, Xuan Chuan Mao Ze Dong Si Xiang, Han Wei Mao Ze Dong Si Xiang (Xiàng Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí De Hǎo ZhànShì Liú Yīng​Jūn TóngZhì XuéXí. XuéXí Máo​ Zé​Dōng​ Sī​Xiǎng, GuànChè Máo​ Zé​Dōng​ Sī​Xiǎng, Xuān​Chuán Máo​ Zé​Dōng​ Sī​Xiǎng, HànWèi Máo​ Zé​Dōng​ Sī​Xiǎng.). 向毛主席的好战士刘英军同志学习。 学习毛泽东思想，贯彻毛泽东思想，宣传毛泽东思想，捍卫毛泽东思想。(向毛主席的好戰士劉英軍同志學習。 學習毛澤東思想，貫徹毛澤東思想，宣傳毛澤東思想，捍衛毛澤東思想。)
  - Determined to be the revolution's powerful next generation. Li Zhi Zuo Jian Qiang De Ge Ming Hou Dai. (LìZhì Zuò JiānQiáng De GéMìng HòuDài). 立志做坚强的革命后代。(立志做堅強的革命後代。)
  - The People and the Army are United Like One Person! Let's See Who On Earth Can Be Oppose Us! Jun Nub Tuan Jie Ru Yi Ren, Shi Kan Tian Xia Shei Neng Di! (JūnMín TuánJié Rú Yī Rén, Shì Kàn TiānXià Shéi Néng Dí!). 军民团结如一人，试看天下谁能敌！（軍民團結如一人，試看天下誰能敵！）
  - Grasp revolution and promote production：Resolutely smash the new counterattack by the capitalist reactionary line! Zhua Ge Ming Cu Sheng Chan: Fen Sui Zi Chan Jie Ji Fan Dong Lu Xian De Xin Fan Pu (Zhuā GéMìng Cù ShēngChǎn: FěnSuì ZīChǎnJiēJí FǎnDòng LùXiàn De Xīn FǎnPū.). 抓革命促生产：粉碎资产阶级反动路线的新反扑！(抓革命促生產：粉碎資產階級反動路線的新反撲！)
  - Drag out the counterrevolutionary revisionist elements and expose them! Ba Fan Ge Ming Xiu Zheng Zhu Yi Fen Zi Jiu Chu Lai Shi Zhong (Bǎ FǎnGéMìng XiūZhèngZhǔYì FènZǐ JiūChūLái ShìZhòng). 把反革命修正主义分子揪出来示众！(把反革命修正主義份子揪出來示眾！)
  - Quotations from Chairman Mao Tse-tung: We are not only good at destroying the old world, we are also good at building the new. Wo Mao Zhu Xi Yu Lu: Wo Men Bu Dan Shan Yu Po Huai Yi Ge Jiu Shi Jie, Wo Men Hai Jiang Shan Yu Jian She Yi Ge Xin Shi Jie. (Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí​ Yǔ​Lù WǒMen BùDàn ShànYú PòHuài YīGè Jiù​ ShìJiè, WǒMen Hái Jiāng ShànYú JiànShè YīGè Xīn ShìJiè.). 毛主席语录：我们不但善于破坏一个旧世界，我们还将善于建设一个新世界。(毛主席語錄：我們不但善於破壞一個舊世界，我們還將善於建設一個新世界。)
  - Overthrow Soviet Revisionism! Smash the dog head of Brezhnev! Smash the dog head of Kosygin! Da Dao Su Xiu! Za Lan Bo Lie Ri Nie Fu De Gou Tou! Za Lan Ke Xi Jin De Gou Tou! (DǎDǎo SūXiū! ZáLàn Bó​Liè​Rì​Niè​Fū De GǒuTóu! ZáLàn Kē​Xī​Jīn De GǒuTóu!). 打倒苏修！砸烂勃列日涅夫的狗头！砸烂柯西金的狗头！(打倒蘇修！ 砸爛勃列日涅夫的狗頭！ 砸爛柯西金的狗頭！)
  - The people's army is a staunch pillar of the proletariat's democratic dictatorship. Zhong Guo Ren Min Jie Fang Jun Shi Wu Chan Jie Ji Zhuan Zheng De Jian Qiang Zhu Shi. (Zhōng​Guó​ Rén​Mín​ Jiě​Fàng​Jūn Shì WúChǎnJiēJí ZhuānZhèng De JiānQiáng ZhùShí.). 中国人民解放军是无产阶级专政的坚强柱石。 (中國人民解放軍是無產階級專政的堅強柱石。)
  - Make manifest the revolutionary "three-in-one combination": Take away the power of those party authorities taking the capitalist road! Shi Xian Ge Ming De "San Jie He": Duo Zou Zi Ben Zhu Yi Dao Lu Dang Quan Pai De Quan. (ShíXiàn GéMìng De "SānJiéHé": Duó Zǒu ZīBěnZhǔYì DàoLù DāngQuánPài De Quán). 实现革命的“三结合”：夺走资本主义道路当权派的权 (實現革命的 "三結合"：奪走資本主義道路當權派的權)
  - Hold high the red banner of great Mao Zedong Thought - Stir up a new wave of great revolutionary criticism - Meet the latest counterattack of the Chinese Khrushchevist heads. Gao Ju Mao Ze Dong Si Xiang Wei Da Hong Qi, Xian Qi Ge Ming Da Pi Pan Xin Gao Chao: Ying Tou Tong Ji Zhong Guo He Lu Xiao Fu De Xin Fan Pu. (GāoJǔ Máo​ Zé​Dōng​ Sī​Xiǎng WěiDà HóngQí, XiānQǐ GéMìng Dà PīPàn Xīn GāoCháo: YíngTóuTòngJī Zhōng​Guó Hè​Lǔ​Xiǎo​Fu De Xīn FǎnPū). 高举毛泽东思想伟大红旗，掀起革命大批判新高潮：迎头痛击中国赫鲁晓夫的新反扑 (高舉毛澤東思想偉大紅旗，掀起革命大批判新高潮：迎頭痛擊中國赫魯曉夫的新反撲)
  - Learn from Chairman Mao’s good fighter, comrade Wang Jie! Xiang Mao Zhu Xi De Hao Zhan Shi Wang Jie Tong Zhi Xue Xi (Xiàng Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí De Hǎo ZhànShì Wáng Jié TóngZhì XuéXí). 向毛主席的好战士王杰同志学习！(向毛主席的好戰士王傑同志學習)
  - Long live the proletariat’s seizure of power! The final days of the masters of the bourgeoisie have come! Wu Chan Jie Jie Duo Quan Wan Sui! Zi Ben Jie Ji Lao Ye Men De Mo Ri Dao Le (WúChǎnJiēJí DuóQuán WànSuì! ZīChǎnJiēJí LǎoYéMen De MòRì Dào Le). 无产阶级夺权万岁！资产阶级老爷们的末日到了! (無產階級奪權萬歲！ 資產階級老爺們的末日到了！)
  - We are Chairman Mao's little red soldiers. Wo Men Shi Mao Zhu Xi De Hong Xiao Bing (WǒMen Shì Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí De Hóng Xiǎo Bīng). 我们是毛主席的红小兵 (我們是毛主席的紅小兵)
  - Highest order: The attitude of Communists towards any person who has made mistakes in his work should be one of persuasion in order to help him change and start afresh and not one of exclusion, unless he is incorrigible. We welcome revolutionary cadres to rise in rebellion. Zui Gao Zhi Shi: Gong Chan Dang Yuan Dui Yu Zai Gong Zuo Zhong Fan Guo Cuo Wu De Ren Men, Chu Le Bu Ke Jiu Yao Zhe Wai, Bu Shi Cai Qu Pai Chi Tai Du, Er Shi Cai Qu Gui Quan Tai Du, Shi Zhi Fan Ran Gai Jin, Qi Jiu Tu Xin. Huan Ying Ge Ming Gan Bu Qi Lai Zao Fan (Zuì Gāo ZhǐShì: Gòng​Chǎn​Dǎng​Yuán DuìYú Zài GōngZuò Zhōng Fàn Guò CuòWù De RénMen, ChúLe BùKěJiùYào Zhě Wài, BùShì CǎiQǔ PáiChì TàiDu, érShì CǎiQǔ GuīQuàn TàiDu, Shǐ Zhī FānRán GǎiJìn, QìJiùTúXīn. HuānYíng GéMìng GànBù QǐLai ZàoFǎn). 最高指示：共产党员对于在工作中犯过错误的人们，除了不可救药者外，不是采取排斥态度，而是采取规劝态度，使之翻然改进，弃旧图新。欢迎革命干部起来造反 (最高指示：共產黨員對於在工作中犯過錯誤的人們，除了不可救藥者外，不是採取排斥態度，而是採取規勸態度，使之翻然改進， 棄舊圖新。 歡迎革命幹部起來造反)
  - Learn from Chairman Mao’s good fighter comrade Liu Yingjun! Xiang Mao Zhu Xi De Hao Zhan Shi Liu Ying Jun Tong Zhi Xue Xi (Xiàng Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí De Hǎo ZhànShì Liú YīngJùn TóngZhì XuéXí!) 向毛主席的好战士刘英俊同志学习! (向毛主席的好戰士劉英俊同志學習！)
  - Learn from the Communist fighter Cai Yongxiang who devoted himself to the people. Xiang Yi Xin Wei Gong De Gong Chan Zhu Yi Zhan Shi Cai Yong Xiang Tong Zhi Xue Xi. (Xiàng YīXīnWèiGōng De GòngChǎnZhǔYì ZhànShì Cài Yǒngxiáng TóngZhì XuéXí). 向一心为公的共产主义战士蔡永祥同志学习 (向一心為公的共產主義戰士蔡永祥同志學習)
  - Imperialism and its running dogs are bound to lose! The Arabian people are bound to win! Di Guo Zhu Yi Ji Qi Zou Gou Bi Bai! A La Bo Ren Min Bi Sheng! (DìGuóZhǔYì JíQí ZǒuGǒu Bì Bài! Ā​Lā​Bó Rén​Mín Bì Shèng!). 帝国主义及其走狗必败！阿拉伯人民必胜！(帝國主義及其走狗必敗！ 阿拉伯人民必勝！)
  - The force at the core leading our cause forward is the Chinese Communist Party. The theoretical foundation guiding our thinking is Marxism-Leninism. Mao Zedong. Ling Dao Wo Men Shi Ye De He Xin Li Liang Shi Zhong Guo Gong Chan Dang, Zhi Dao Wo Men Si Xiang Li Lun Ji Chu Shi Ma Ke Si - Lie Ning Zhu Yi (LǐngDǎo WǒMen ShìYè De HéXīn LìLiang Shì Zhōng​Guó​ Gòng​Chǎn​Dǎng, ZhǐDǎo WǒMen SīXiǎng LǐLùnJīChǔ Shì Mǎ​Kè​Sī​ · Liè​Níng​Zhǔ​Yì​. Máo​ Zé​dōng). 领导我们事业的核心力量是中国共产党，指导我们思想理论基础是马克思列宁主义。毛泽东 (領導我們事業的核心力量是中國共產黨，指導我們思想理論基礎是馬克思・列寧主義。 毛澤東)
  - The words of Chairman Mao are like the sun, each word, each sentence shines golden lights, lights up the hearts of fighters, illuminating their path in work and study. Mao Zhu Xi Zhu Zuo Xiang Tai Yang, Zi Zi Ju Ju Shan Jin Guang. Zhao De Zhan Shi Xin Li Liang, Gong Zuo Xue Xi You Fang Xiang. (Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí ZhùZuò Xiàng TàiYang, ZìZìJùJù Shǎn Jīn Guāng. ZhàoDé ZhànShì XīnLi Liàng, GōngZuò Xué​Xí Yǒu FāngXiàng). 毛主席著作象太阳，字字句句闪金光。照得战士心里亮，工作学习有方向。(毛主席著作象太陽，字字句句閃金光。 照得戰士心裡亮，工作學習有方向。)
  - Long Live the Victory of Chairman Mao's Revolutionary Line in Literature and Art! Mao Zhu Xi De Ge Ming Wen Yi Lu Xian Sheng Li Wan Sui (Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí De GéMìng WénYì LùXiàn ShèngLì WànSuì). 毛主席的革命文艺路线胜利万岁 (毛主席的革命文藝路線勝利萬歲 )
  - Long Live the Invincible Mao Zedong Thought! Zhan Wu Bu Sheng De Mao Ze Dong Si Xiang Wan Sui (ZhànWúBùShèng De Máo​ Zé​dōng​ Sī​Xiǎng WànSuì). 战无不胜的毛泽东思想万岁！(戰無不勝的毛澤東思想萬歲！)
  - Oppose economism: destroy the new counter-offensive of the capitalist class reactionary line. Fan Dui Jing Ji Zhu Yi! Fen Sui Zi Chan Jie Ji Fan Dong Lu Xian De Xin Fan Pu (FǎnDuì JīngJìZhǔYì! FěnSuì ZīChǎnJiēJí FǎnDòng LùXiàn De Xīn FǎnPū). 反对经济主义！粉碎资产阶级反动路线的新反扑 (反對經濟主義！粉碎資產階級反動路線的新反撲)
  - Long live Chairman Mao, our great tutor, great leader, great commander-in-chief, and great helmsman! Wo Men Wei Da De Dao Shi, Wei Da De Ling Xiu, Wei Da De Tong Shuai, Wei Da De Duo Shou Mao Zhu Xi Wan Sui! (WǒMen WěiDà De DǎoShī, WěiDà De LǐngXiù, WěiDà De TǒngShuài, WěiDà De DuòShǒu Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí WànSuì!). 我们伟大的导师，伟大的领袖，伟大的统帅，伟大的舵手毛主席万岁! (我們偉大的導師，偉大的領袖， 偉大的統帥， 偉大的舵手毛主席萬歲！)
  - Daring to make sun and moon shine in new skies. Gan Jiao Ri Yue Haun Xin Tian (Gǎn Jiào RìYuè Huàn Xīn Tiān). 敢教日月换新天 (敢教日月換新天)
  - At Tiananmen, Chairman Mao and Comrade Lin Biao inspect the million-man army of the Cultural Revolution. Mao Zhu Xi He Lin Biao Tong Zhi Zai Tian An Men Shang Jian Yue Bai Wan Wen Hua Ge Ming Da Jun (Máo​ Zhǔ​xí Hé Lín​ Biāo TóngZhì Zài Tiān​'ān​Mén Shàng JiǎnYuè BǎiWàn WénHuà GéMìng DàJūn). 毛主席和林彪同志在天安门上检阅百万文化革命大军 (毛主席和林彪同志在天安門上檢閱百萬文化革命大軍)
  - Long live Chairman Mao, our great tutor, great leader, great commander- in- chief and great helmsman! Wo Men Wei Da De Dao Shi, Wei Da De Ling Xiu, Wei Da De Tong Shuai, Wei Da De Duo Shou Mao Zhu Xi Wan Sui! (WǒMen WěiDà De DǎoShī, WěiDà De LǐngXiù, WěiDà De TǒngShuài, WěiDà De DuòShǒu Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí WànSuì!). 我们伟大的导师，伟大的领袖，伟大的统帅，伟大的舵手毛主席万岁! (我們偉大的導師，偉大的領袖， 偉大的統帥， 偉大的舵手毛主席萬歲！)
  - Communist fighter Cai Yongxiang who devoted himself to the people. Yi Xin Wei Gong De Gong Chan Zhu Yi Zhan Shi ---- Cai Yong Xiang (YīXīnWèiGōng De GòngChǎnZhǔYì ZhànShì ---- Cài Yǒngxiáng). 一心为公的共产主义战士——蔡永祥 (一心為公的共產主義戰士 ---- 蔡永祥)
  - Political power grows out of the barrel of a gun. Qiang Gan Zi Li Mian Chu Zheng Quan (QiāngGǎnZi LǐMiàn Chū ZhèngQuán). 枪杆子里面出政权 (槍桿子裡面出政權)
  - Use the "Talks" as weapon to destroy the counterrevolutionary revisionist black line of literature and art. Yi 《Jiang Hua》Wei Wu Qi Che Di Cui Hui Fan Ge Ming Xiu Zheng Zhu Yi Wen Yi Hei Xian (Yǐ 《JiǎngHuà》Wèi WǔQì ChèDǐ CuīHuǐ FǎnGéMìng XiūZhèngZhǔYì WénYì Hēi Xiàn). 以《讲话》为武器彻底摧毁反革命修正主义文艺黑线 (以《講話》為武器徹底摧毀反革命修正主義文藝黑線)
  - Use Maoist thoughts as weapon, smash all ghosts and monsters, totally expose, totally criticize, totally overthrow, not retreating until total victory. Yi Mao Ze Dong Si Xiang Wei Wu Qi, Heng Sao Yi Qie Niu Gui She Shen, Che Di Jie Lu, Che Di Pi Pan, Che Di Da Dao, Bu Huo Quan Sheng Jue Bu Shou Bing (Yǐ Máo​ Zé​dōng​ Sī​Xiǎng Wèi WǔQì, HéngSǎo YīQiè NiúGuǐ ShéShén, ChèDǐ JiēLù, ChèDǐ PīPàn, ChèDǐ DǎDǎo, Bù Huò QuánShèng JuéBù ShōuBīng ). 以毛泽东思想为武器，横扫一切牛鬼蛇神，彻底揭露，彻底批判，彻底打倒，不获全胜决不收兵 (以毛澤東思想為武器，橫掃一切牛鬼蛇神，徹底揭露，徹底批判，徹底打倒，不獲全勝決不收兵)
  - Learn from comrade Liu Yingjun, study the highest orders. Xiang Liu Ying Jun Tong Zhi Xue Xi, Xue Xi Zui Gao Zhi Shi (Xiàng Liú YīngJùn TóngZhì XuéXí, XuéXí Zuì Gāo ZhǐShì). 向刘英俊同志学习，学习最高指示 (向劉英俊同志學習，學習最高指示)
  - Long live Chairman Mao. Mao Zhu Xi Wan Sui (Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí WànSuì). 毛主席万岁 (毛主席萬歲)
  - Chairman Mao is the red sun in the hearts of people around the world. Mao Zhu Xi Shi Shi Jie Ren Min Xin Zhong De Hong Tai Yang (Máo​ ZhǔXí Shì ShìJiè RénMín XīnZhōng De Hóng TàiYang). 毛主席是世界人民心中的红太阳 (毛主席是世界人民心中的紅太陽)
  - Art and culture must serve workers, peasants, and soldiers. It must serve proletarian politics! Wen Yi Wei Gong Nong Bing Fu Wu, Wei Wu Chan Jie Ji Zheng Zhi Fu Wu (WénYì Wèi GōngNóngBīng FúWù, Wèi WúChǎnJiēJí ZhèngZhì FúWù!). 文艺为工农兵服务，为无产阶级政治服务！(文藝為工農兵服務, 為無產階級政治服務！)
  - The heroic drilling team, who holds high the red banner of great Mao Zedong Thought. Gao Ju Mao Ze Dong Si Xiang Wei Da Hong Qi De Ying Xiong Zuan Jing Dui (GāoJǔ Máo​ Zé​dōng​ Sī​Xiǎng WěiDà HóngQí De YīngXióng ZuànJǐng Duì). 高举毛泽东思想伟大红旗的英雄钻井队 (高舉毛澤東思想偉大紅旗的英雄鑽井隊)
  - Hold high the red banner of great Mao Zedong Thought to wage the Great Proletarian Cultural Revolution to the end. Revolution is no crime, to rebel is justified. Gao Ju Mao Ze Dong Si Xiang Wei Da Hong Qi Ba Wu Chan Jie Ji Wen Hua Da Ge Ming Jin Xing Dao Di. Ge Ming Wu Zui, Zao Fan You Li. (GāoJǔ Máo​ Zé​dōng​ Sī​Xiǎng WěiDà HóngQí Bǎ WúChǎnJiēJí Wén​huà​ Dà​Gé​Mìng JìnXíng DàoDǐ. GéMìng WúZuì, ZàoFǎn YǒuLǐ). 高举毛泽东思想伟大红旗把无产阶级文化大革命进行到底。革命无罪，造反有理。(高舉毛澤東思想偉大紅旗把無產階級文化大革命進行到底。 革命無罪，造反有理。)
  - The Peoples' Liberation Army strongly supports proletariat revolutionaries. Jie Fang Jun Jian Jue Zhi Chi Wu Chan Jie Ji Ge Ming Pai (Jiě​Fàng​Jūn JiānJué ZhīChí WúChǎnJiēJí GéMìng Pài). 解放军坚决支持无产阶级革命派 (解放軍堅決支持無產階級革命派)
  - Chairman Mao, our great tutor, great leader, great commander-in-chief and great helmsman inspects the armies of the Cultural Revolution. Wo Men Wei Da De Dao Shi, Wei Da De Ling Xiu, Wei Da De Tong Shuai, Wei Da De Duo Shou Mao Zhu Xi Jian Yue Wen Hua Ge Ming Da Jun (WǒMen WěiDà De DǎoShī, WěiDà De LǐngXiù, WěiDà De TǒngShuài, WěiDà De DuòShǒu Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí JiǎnYuè WénHuà GéMìng DàJūn). 我们伟大的导师，伟大的领袖，伟大的统帅，伟大的舵手毛主席检阅文化革命大军 (我們偉大的導師，偉大的領袖， 偉大的統帥， 偉大的舵手毛主席檢閱文化革命大軍)
  - Mao Zedong Thoughts lights up the path of proletariat Cultural Revolution. Mao Ze Dong Si Xiang De Yang Guang Zhao Liang Wu Chan Jie Jie Wen Hua Da Ge Ming De Dao Lu (Máo​ Zé​dōng​ Sī​Xiǎng De YángGuāng ZhàoLiàng WúChǎnJiēJí Wén​Huà​ Dà​Gé​Mìng​ De DàoLù). 毛泽东思想的阳光照亮无产阶级文化大革命的道路 (毛澤東思想的陽光照亮無產階級文化大革命的道路)
  - Unite together, fight together, achieve victory together. Tuan Jie Zai Yi Qi, Zhan Dou Zai Yi Qi, Sheng Li Zai Yi Qi (TuánJié ZàiYīQǐ, ZhànDòu ZàiYīQǐ, ShèngLì ZàiYīQǐ). 团结在一起，战斗在一起，胜利在一起 (團結在一起，戰鬥在一起，勝利在一起)
  - Chairman Mao is the red sun in our hearts. Mao Zhu Xi Shi Wo Men Xin Zhong De Hong Tai Yang (Máo​ Zhǔ​xí Shì WǒMen XīnZhōng De Hóng TàiYang). 毛主席是我们心中的红太阳 (毛主席是我們心中的紅太陽)
  - Unite the proletarian insurgents, wage the Great Proletarian Cultural Revolution to the end. Ge Ming Zao Fan Pai Lian He Qi Lai, Ba Wu Chan Jie Ji Wen Hua Da Ge Ming Jin Xing Dao Di (GéMìng ZàoFǎnPài LiánHé Qi Lai, Bǎ WúChǎnJiēJí Wén​huà​ Dà​Gé​Mìng JìnXíng DàoDǐ). 革命造反派联合起来，把无产阶级文化大革命进行到底！(革命造反派聯合起來，把無產階級文化大革命進行到底。)
  - [Our purpose is] to ensure that literature and art fit well into the whole revolutionary machine as a component part, that they operate as powerful weapons for uniting and educating the people and for attacking and destroying the enemy, and that they help the people fight the enemy with one heart and one mind. Mao Zedong. Yao Shi Wen Yi Hen Hao De Cheng Wei Zheng Ge Ge Ming Ji Qi De Yi Ge Zu Cheng Bu Fen, Zuo Wei Tuan Jie Ren Min, Jiao Yu Ren Mine, Da Ji Di Ren, Xiao Mie Di Ren De You Li Wu Qi, Bang Zhu Ren Min Tong Xin Tong De De He Di Ren Zuo Dou Zheng. Mao Ze Dong (Yào Shǐ WénYì Hěn Hǎo De ChéngWéi ZhěngGè GéMìng JīQì De YīGè ZǔChéngBùFèn, ZuòWéi TuánJié RénMín, JiàoYù RénMín, DǎJī DíRén, XiāoMiè DíRén De YǒuLì WǔQì, BāngZhù RénMín TóngXīnTóngDé De Hé DíRén Zuò DòuZhēng. Máo​ Zé​dōng). 要使文艺很好地成为整个革命机器的一个组成部分，作为团结人民，教育人民，打击敌人，消灭敌人的有力武器，帮助人民同心同德地和敌人作斗争。毛泽东 (要使文藝很好地成為整個革命機器的一個組成部分，作為團結人民，教育人民，打擊敵人，消滅敵人的有力武器，幫助人民同心同德地和敵人作鬥爭。 毛澤東)
  - Long live Chairman Mao, our great tutor, great leader, great commander-in-chief and great helmsman! Wo Men Wei Da De Dao Shi, Wei Da De Ling Xiu, Wei Da De Tong Shuai, Wei Da De Duo Shou Mao Zhu Xi Wan Sui! (WǒMen WěiDà De DǎoShī, WěiDà De LǐngXiù, WěiDà De TǒngShuài, WěiDà De DuòShǒu Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí WànSuì!). 我们伟大的导师，伟大的领袖，伟大的统帅，伟大的舵手毛主席万岁！ (我們偉大的導師，偉大的領袖， 偉大的統帥， 偉大的舵手毛主席萬歲！)
  - Fear neither hardship nor death. Learn from comrade Wang Jie's spiritual mind which devotes himself whole-heartedly to revolution. Yi Bu Pa Ku, Er Bu Pa Si. Xue Xi Wang Jie Tong Zhi Yi Xin Wei Ge Ming De Chong Gao Jing Shen. (Yī BùPà Kǔ, èr BùPà Sǐ. XuéXí Wáng Jié TóngZhì YīXīn Wèi GéMìng De ChóngGāo JīngShén). 一不怕苦，二不怕死。学习王杰同志一心为革命的崇高精神 (一不怕苦，二不怕死。 學習王傑同志一心為革命的崇高精神)
  - The Peoples' Liberation Army is a staunch supporter of proletarian revolutionaries. Zhong Guo Ren Min Jie Fang Jun Shi Wu Chan Jie Ji Ge Ming Pai De Jian Qiang Hou Dun (Zhōng​Guó​ Rén​Mín​ Jiě​Fàng​Jūn Shì WúChǎnJiēJí Pài De JiānQiáng HòuDùn). 中国人民解放军是无产阶级革命派的坚强后盾 (中國人民解放軍是無產階級革命派的堅強後盾)
  - Long live our great, beloved leader Chairman Mao. Wo Men Zui Jing Ai De Wei Da Ling Xiu Mao Zhu Xi Wan Sui (WǒMen Zuì Jìng-ài De WěiDà LǐngXiù Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí WànSuì). 我们最敬爱的伟大领袖毛主席万岁 (我們最敬愛的偉大領袖毛主席萬歲)
  - Answer Chairman Mao's call with gusto, commence large-scale movements to support the army and to cherish the people. Jian Jue Xiang Ying Mao Zhu Xi Hao Zhao Zhan Kai Da Gui Mo De Re Lie De Yong Jun Ai Min Yun Dong. (JiānJué XiǎngYìng Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí HàoZhào ZhǎnKāi DàGuīMó De RèLiè De YōngJūn Ài​Mín YùnDòng). 坚决响应毛主席号召展开大规模的热烈的拥军爱民运动 (堅決響應毛主席號召展開大規模的熱烈的擁軍愛民運動)